<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<packageId>Buggy.RimWorldMod.MutatedPawn</packageId>
	<name>Mutated Pawn</name>
	<author>Buggy</author>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.4</li>
	</supportedVersions>	
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
        	<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
        </li>
		<li>
            <packageId>UnlimitedHugs.HugsLib</packageId>
            <displayName>HugsLib</displayName>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/UnlimitedHugs/RimworldHugsLib/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/818773962</steamWorkshopUrl>
        </li>
		<li>
		    <packageId>ludeon.rimworld.biotech</packageId>
		    <displayName>Biotech</displayName>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>   
	<description>Allow any pawn a chance to have random genes with the following configurations:
[list]
[*]3 different chances to have mutations, each with its own max mutation number and chance.
[*]Chance to develop a random mutation for a pawn with a growing carcinoma. Check every 5000 ticks (a day has 60k ticks). Set to 0% to disable this. Thanks Jdalt40 for the suggestion.
[*]Chance to develop a random mutation for a pawn with moderate (or worse) toxic buildup. Check every 5000 ticks (a day has 60k ticks). Set to 0% to disable this. Thanks CrackaJack for the suggestion.
[*]White list and black list mechanism to control the list of available genes for mutation. I have troubles create a good UX for these options. I have to resort to text field input. Sorry guys! You can find the name for the genes if you use the included options to print them all to dev console log.
[*]Mutated genes can be endogene or xenogene.
[*]Allow archite genes.
[*]The minimum metabolic efficiency allowed, used ONLY by this mod, when deciding a mutation can happen or not. Thank 沙坡村大师 for the suggestion.
[/list]

Mutated genes have yellow border. Thanks to erdelf for suggestions about using ThingComp.

It can be safely added mid-game and should not conflict with any mods. If added mid-game, it does not affected existing pawns.

I used HugsLib to handle settings windows. Many thanks to UnlimitedHugs (RimworldHugsLib), Jaxe (Interaction Bubble) and cbrintnall (EzOutfit) and  for their codes and hard works!

If you like this mod, maybe check out my other one:
Permanent Injury Letter https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2592535960
More Biotech Letters https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2889303626
Billed Deep Drill https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2593197871

It would be great to receive feedback, suggestions or pointers on how to improve. Hope these mods help!

Cheers!

Version history
[b]v0.81[/b]
[list]
[*]Handle null comp properly. Many thanks to Taemaly_UA!
[/list]
[b]v0.8[/b]
[list]
[*]Do not check for toxic buildup or carcinoma mutation if a pawn is in crytosleep. Thanks fruitcake662!
[/list]
[b]v0.7[/b]
[list]
[*]Slightly improve the process of choosing random genes.
[/list]
[b]v0.6[/b]
[list]
[*]Allow mutation for a pawn with moderate (or worse) toxic buildup.
[*]Allow white list and black list mechanism.
[*]Move carcinoma mutation to the mod comp class.
[*]Depends on HugsLib for setting windows.
[/list]
[b]v0.5[/b]
[list]
[*]Draw yellow border around mutated genes.
[*]Fix a bug where the same gene are chosen multiple times for mutation, which leads to fail pawn generation.
[/list]
[b]v0.4[/b]
[list]
[*]Allow mutation for a pawn with a growing carcinoma.
[/list]
[b]v0.3[/b]
[list]
[*]Break mutation process into 3 different groups, each with its own max mutation and chance.
[/list]
[b]v0.2[/b]
[list]
[*]Expand the option to allow flexible minimum allowed metabolic efficiency.
[/list]
[b]v0.1[/b]
[list]
[*]Initial release.
[/list]</description>
</ModMetaData>